Name: Age: 29

Mohamed Ali Abdellatif

Jop title: Software Engineer

Conditions required for Software quality and testing specialist

At least 5 years of practical experience in web programmin.

☐ Experience and knowledge of the PHP programming language and understanding of MVC design patterns.

must have good knowledge and previous project using Drupal CMS.

must have expert knowledge in using Laravel and building Rest-API.

have knowledge of connecting to SSO system is better. must

must have a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science or its equivalent.

Proficiency in English and Arabic, spoken and written.

Additional experience or skills

working with laravel, drupal, codeigniter, php native					
html , css , javascript , jquery, ajax					
docker , git , github api , rest api , pusher , firebase					
sysytem design , SOLID princible , design pattern					
SQL and mysql, postgree					

Mohamed Ali Abd Ellatif

Address: Egypt / Cairo governorate

Nationality:: Egyptian

Objectiv

To leverage my experience in architecting and developing websites for major industries into challenging and exciting product

Technologies

Programming Languages: php, , Javascript

Php Tech: php native ,laravel,Codeigniter, drupal,

FrontEnd Tech: Html5, css3, bootstrap, jquery, ajax, json, Vue js

(basics)

Addiotnal Skills: ,Agile ,Scrum,Design pattern oop,webservice (Api) ,

GoLang (basics), , graphql(basics) , python,Flutter (Basics)

Database: MySql & Sql Version control and other tools: Git, Github,

Gitlab, bitbucket Jira, Bitrix, Server Side: pusher,

Firebase, socket.io, Laravel webSockets

Education

Assiut University- B.Sc in Computer Science (September 2013 - June 2017)

Experience

1- Naseej company - software developer (Apr 2022 - Present) senior drupal developer and php at naseej company at cairo.

2- dimofinf company - back-end developer (Aug 2020 - Apr2022) backend developer (laravel) at dimofinf company at cairo 3- sahl solutaion company - back-end developer (march 2020 – Aug 2020)

backend developer (laravel) at sahl solutaion company at cairo
4- minvotech company - back-end developer (July 2019 - Present)
backend developer (laravel) at minvotech company at cairo
5- invetechs company - back-end developer (march: 2019 – july: 2019) backend developer (laravel) at invetechs company at cairo
6- smart ware company - php developer (August 2017 - jan 2018) trainer and developer at smart ware startup company at assuit
Freelancing as php developer(2016-2017)

Projects

1- portal

Architecture : Drupal CMS

Front End Technologies: React

Back End Technologies: Drupal 9, Solr

2 - Weqaia

Architecture : Drupal CMS

Front End Technologies: twigs
Back End Technologies: Drupal 9

3 - hanklane

Architecture: Drupal CMS

Front End Technologies : twigs Back End Technologies : Drupal 9

4 - Auc (Arabic Union Catalog)

Architecture: Drupal CMS

Front End Technologies: React

Back End Technologies: Drupal 9, Solr

5 - El Marsad App

https://play.google.com/store/

apps/details?id=com.dimofinf

.marsad News Application

Features:

- . Enable admin to manage all application dashboard
- . Enable users add browse categories and news
- . Enable users to subscribe packages using payment gateways (paytabs, paypal)
- .Enable user to comment like , dislike

Architecture : MVC Architecture Front End Technologies : flutter

Back End Technologies: Laravel 7, Passport, payment gateways

(paytabs, paypal)

6 - المسابقات Competition website project link

Features:

- . Enable users to compitate each others
- . Enable users joins rooms and answer questions
- . Enable users to earn money using payment gateways (paypal)

Architecture : MVC Architecture Front End Technologies : React

Back End Technologies: Laravel 7, Passport, payment gateways

(paypal)

7 - Save points website

multivendor app and pos

system https://savepoints.sa/

Features:

- . Enable merchants to create their store
- . Enable users collect points frommerchants
- . Enable users to replace points on products

Architecture : MVC Architecture Front End Technologies : React

Back End Technologies: Laravel 7, Passport, payment gateways

(paypal)

8 - Sola App

Ecommerce

Application

Features:

- . Enable admin to manage all application dashboard
- . Enable users add browse categories and products, ads, offers
- . Enable users to add product and to cart
- . Enable user to order and track there orders

Architecture: MVC Architecture

Front End Technologies: java andriod

Back End Technologies: Laravel 7, Passport

9 - Buffet-System

System to help Manage Buffet Resources

Features:

- . Enable admin to manage all sytstem dashboard
- . Enable admin add items , addpresets
- . Enable emolyee to add own items and order and presets
- . Enable emolyee to add item to cart
- . Enable buffet emolyee to receive and control order

Architecture : MVC Architecture

Front End Technologies: Rreact js ,html5, css3,

bootstrap4, javascript

Back End Technologies: Laravel 7, Passport, QrCode

10 - Cut Egypt

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cut&hl=en&gl= US Cut Egypt app - Hairdresser app to book the best barbershop salon.

Features:

- Barbershop salons & spa search based on yourlocation.
- Delivery barber Booking at home or office.
- Know the best barbershop salon work dates.
- Rate the barber or the client through Cut Egyptreviews.
- Searching for best Barbershop salon based on barber rate.
- Booking at seconds within any time7/24.
- Choosing your favorite Barber through Cut Egyptapp.
- Get best Exclusive cut offers on best barbershopsalons.
- Get immediate push notification for your booking.
- Explore best & the most popular cuts through CutEgypt.
- Explore Barbershop Salons prices & services without making any call through Cut Egypt.
 Reading comments & rate Barbershop Salons services.
- Cut Egypt app supports Arabic language & English Language.

Architecture: MVCArchitecture

Mobile App Technologies: objective c, java

Back End Technologies : Codelgniter Framwork

11 - Yalla-Furnish https://yalla-furnish.net/

Website to help showrooms and users to offer there furniture Features:

- . Enable admin to manage all websitedashboard
- . Enable showroom admin to manage showroom, add products, add ideas, add topics 13- Enable users to add products and share and compare products
- . Enable users to design their home and import the final image
- . Enable users to chat with each others and comment on their posts

Architecture: MVC Architecture

Front End Technologies: html5, css3, bootstrap4, javascript

Back End Technologies: Laravel, 5.6

12 - Bartita https://staging.bartita.com/

Website to help stores and users to offer there products Features:

- . Enable admin to manage all website dashboard
- . Enable Stores admin to manage Store, add products
- . Enable users to add products
- . Enable users to chat with each others

Architecture: MVC Architecture

Front End Technologies: html5, css3, bootstrap3, javascript

Back End Technologies: Laravel, 5.6

(Erp System) كالنبوية لسنة-13

Features:

- . Enable managements to manage dashboard
- . Enable managements to assign roles on employees
- . Enable Employees to connect with each others
- . Enable Employees to manage their roles
- . Enable Employees to CRUD hadiths
- . Enable Employees to advanced search for hadiths
- . manage over 1 million hadiths

And many other functions and features

Architecture : MVC Architecture

Front End Technologies: html5, css3, bootstrap3, javascript

Back End Technologies: Laravel, 6

14- األحكام أحاديث (<u>https://ahkam.ithraa.sa/ethraa</u>) Erp System and public website for visitors

Features:

- 1- Enable managements to manage dashboard
- 2- Enable managements to assign roles on employees
- 3- Enable Employees to connect with each others
- 4- Enable Employees to manage their roles
- 5- Enable Employees to CRUD hadiths
- 6- Enable Employees to advanced search for hadiths
- 7- Enable visitors to browse and search for hadiths and its accessories

And many other functions and features

Architecture: MVC Architecture

Front End Technologies: html5, css3, bootstrap3, javascript

Back End Technologies: Laravel, 6

15 - web apis for Mammamiaa application (laravel) (https://mammamiaa.com)

Mamamia Consist of three parts user, Vendor ,Driver To system management for restaurant The user can make order and track his order The driver find nearest order and deliver it Vendor track the order and driver With Google Map And can make invoices And calculate annual bonus And manage his restaurant meals and products Admin manage all system Using Laravel Framework

Architecture : MVC Architecture

Back End Technonlogies: Laravel, 5.6, passport Api Package, Pusher

notification

- 16 Turismo Website (codeiginiter) (final graduationproject)(https://github.com/Mali9/tourismo)
 For hiring tour guides and car owners Tourists who visit egypt can survey the site and they can hire tour guide or car owner The site show all touristic sitesin egypt andshow statistics aboutmost visited touristic places and reviews aboutitfrom visitors
- 17 Jobadge website(Laravel)(https://jobadge.com/)
- 1) Jobadge "Where finding the right candidate is not a problem and the process of getting the right job is an experience and no longer a struggle."
- 2) In Jobadge we create values to live by. Innovation is what we seek in every stage of the process, "Find the best, keep the best " Cover the whole recruitment process through the platform including invitations, scheduling, reminders, evaluation, appreciation and tracking by maintaining open channel with companies.
- 3) Highlight the skilled and distinguished profiles from the crowd to save companies,
- recruiters and candidates time by providing rating, feedback, metrics and video interviews. 4) Building services covering the needs of recruiters and candidates by providing consultation, training and career advice services.
- 5) Building a directory for Freelancers and Part timers willing to increase theirincome.
- 18 Sakeny website (Laravel)(https://www.sakeny.com/)
 Sakeny is Real State WebSite

